

OMAR KARANY

Medical Laboratory Specialist and frontend developer

DETAILS

Alexandria, Egypt omarkarany@gmail.com

PROFILE

As a Medical Lab Specialist with experience in multiple hospitals, I have made significant contributions to the improvement of lab processes and the enhancement of team qualifications. I conducted a thorough analytical study of job systems and provided valuable tips for development, resulting in time and cost savings, problem-solving, and overall process cycle improvement. I have strong communication skills and the ability to work effectively in a team. I am a quick learner and can handle pressure situations with ease. My future goal is to continue growing in my role as a Medical Lab Specialist and contribute to the field of healthcare.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Medical Lab Specialist, Alsaraya Hospital Lab, Alexandria

OCTOBER 2017 - GCTOBER 2020

Performed diverse medical laboratory tests, aiding in disease diagnosis, treatment, and prevention. Analyzed and interpreted results, maintained equipment, and ensured safety and quality compliance. Collaborated with healthcare professionals for accurate and timely outcomes.

Conducted a comprehensive analysis of job systems, implementing strategies for time and resource savings. Provided developmental tips, enhancing process efficiency. Demonstrated strong communication and teamwork, working collaboratively for high-quality patient care. Adapted swiftly to new technologies, thriving in a fast-paced, high-pressure environment. Developed and managed a cohesive team, fostering positivity and productivity.

Medical lab specialist, Alpha hospital lab, Alexandria

JANUARY 2020 - OCTOBER 2020

Good experience at: sampling, chemistry (full automation and semi automation), coagulation tests, hematology tests, microbiology cultures, urine and stool examination.

Medical lab specialist, Mabaret alasafra labs

NOVEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

professional to handle with cobas fully automated analyzers, apply the qc rules and follow up with internal and external controls.

EDUCATION

Bachelor degree of science, faculty of science 'Alazhar university'

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2017

High Diploma of Biochemistry, faculty of science 'Suez canal university'

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2018

Front End Developer Diploma, Almadrsa platform

NOVEMBER 2023 - APRIL 2024

SKILLS Creativity	Problem Solving	
Time Management	Microsoft Office	
Teamwork	Analytical Study	
Process Improvement	Quick Learner	
		_

LANGUAGES

english

arabic